Register of the George Sokolsky Papers, 1916-1962
Hoover Institution Archives
George Sokolsky papers,
1916-1962
59004
Hoover Institution Archives
390 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (164.5 linear feet)
Writings, radio broadcast transcripts, correspondence, printed matter, phonorecords, and photographs, relating to politics, communism, internal security and anti-communist movements in the United States, and to politics and communism in China and elsewhere.
Sokolsky, George E. (George Ephraim), 1893-1962.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1959.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1893 September 5 Born, Utica, New York
1917 B.A., School of Journalism, Columbia University, New York
Editor, Russian Daily News, Petrograd
1918 Assistant Editor, North China Star, Tientsin (T'ien-chin), China
1920-1930 Political correspondent, North China Star. Shanghai correspondent for New York Evening Post, Philadelphia Public Ledger, New York World, London Daily Express, Japan Advertiser
1922 Married Rosalind Phang
1927-1930 Editor, Far Eastern Review
1928 Author, Outlines of Universal History
1932 Author, Tinder Box of Asia
1933 Death of Rosalind Sokolsky
1934 Author, Labor's Fight for Power
1935 Author, We Jews. Married Dorothy Fiske
1935-1940 Contributor, New York Herald Tribune
1938 Author, Labor Crisis in the United States
1939 Author, The American Way of Life
1940-1962 Syndicated newspaper columnist
1948-1961 Commentator, American Broadcasting Company
1948-1962 Director, American Jewish League Against Communism
1962 December 12 Died
American Jewish League against Communism.; Anti-communist movements--United States.; China--Politics and government--20th century.; China.; Communism--China.; Communism--United States.; Communism.; Internal security--United States.; Journalism--United States.; Journalists.; Phonorecords.; Subversive activities--United States.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.; United States--Politics and government.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1930-1961.
  Scope and Contents note
  Awards, certificates, clippings, itineraries, membership cards, memorabilia, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1916-1962.
  Letters arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1920-1962.
  Books, articles, lectures, reports, speeches, and related correspondence, arranged chronologically by title
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS WRITTEN FOR OTHERS, 1938-1962.
  Speeches and writings arranged by name of individual
- ARTICLES AND BROADCAST TRANSCRIPTS, 1936-1962.
  Daily newspaper columns and weekly broadcast transcripts, arranged chronologically
- SUBJECT FILE, 1918-1962.
  Clippings, correspondence, printed matter, and reports, arranged alphabetically by subject
- PRINTED MATTER, 1919-1962.
  Clippings and published material, arranged by physical form
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1919-1962.
  Albums, maps, and reports
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1917-1962.
  Recordings and photographs
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1930-1961
  - Album, with photo reproductions, from Presidents' Advanced Round Table Sessions, 1961. Includes letter (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Articles about Sokolsky. Includes correspondence and invitations (Folder 2)
  - Awards, certficates and commendations. Includes correspondence and invitations (Folder 3)
  - Birthday greetings, 1956 (Folder 4)
  - Codebooks (Bentley's) used by Sokolsky in China (Folder 5)
  - Itineraries. Includes correspondence
    - J. Edgar Hoover Dinner, 1961 (Folder 6)
    - London trip, 1955 (Folder 7)
    - Washington trip, 1961 (Folder 8)
  - Miscellany. Christmas card, commencement program, contract, menu, press pass, cartoon sketch of Sokolsky, hospital visitors' list, and telegram from Francis Cardinal Spellman (Folder 9)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1916-1962
  - General (Box 2)
    - Unidentified (Folder 1)
    - Aa-Al (Folder 2)
    - Am-Ay (Folder 3)
    - Baa-Bay (Folder 4)
    - Be-Bi (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bl-Bo (Folder 2)
    - Bra-Bru (Folder 3)
    - Bu-By (Folder 4)
    - Cai-Cas (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cat-Cl (Folder 2)
    - Cob-Cor (Folder 3)
    - Cos-Cul (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Cum-Cus (Folder 2)
    - Da-De (Folder 3)
    - Di-Dw (Folder 4)
    - Ea-El (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Em-Ey (Folder 2)
    - Fa-Fl (Folder 3)
    - Fo-Fu (Folder 4)
    - Ga-Gi (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Gl-Gre (Folder 2)
    - Gri-Gy (Folder 3)
    - Hac-Han (Folder 4)
    - Har-Haz (Folder 5)
    - Hea-Heu (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Hi-Ho (Folder 2)
    - Hu-Hy (Folder 3)
    - I (Folder 4)
    - Ja-Je (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Jo-Ju (Folder 2)
    - Ka-Ke (Folder 3)
    - Ki-Kn (Folder 4)
    - Ko-Ky (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Lag-Lee (Folder 2)
    - Lef-Llo (Folder 3)
    - Lob-Lyt (Folder 4)
    - Mac-Mag (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Mal-Myl (Folder 2)
    - N (Folder 3)
    - O (Folder 4)
    - P (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Q (Folder 2)
    - R (Folder 3)
    - Sa-Sh (Folder 4)
    - Si-Sm (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Sn-Sw (Folder 2)
    - T (Folder 3)
    - U (Folder 4)
    - V (Folder 5)
    - Wa-We (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Wh-Wi (Folder 2)
    - Wo-Wy (Folder 3)
    - X (Folder 4)
    - Y (Folder 5)
    - Z (Folder 6)
    - Miscellany (Folder 7-10)
  - Abels, Jules, 1951-1959 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Abend, Hallet, 1929-1950 (Folder 2)
  - The Abilene Reporter-News, 1947-1949 (Folder 3)
  - The Academy of Political Science, 1943-1959 (Folder 4)
  - Ackerman, Carl, 1931-1956 (Folder 5)
  - Adelman, Samuel, 1962 (Folder 6)
  - Adler, Luther, 1952-1953 (Folder 7)
  - Affleck, Benjamin, Mr. and Mrs.
    - 1934-1941 (Folder 8)
    - 1942-1947 (Folder 9)
  - Alanson, Bertram, 1948-1950 (Folder 10)
  - Alexander, A. L., 1943-1945 (Folder 11)
  - Alexander, Eben, 1956-1959 (Folder 12)
  - Alexander, Ralph, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Alexander, Robert Clark, 1947-1951 (Folder 2)
  - Alexander, Ruth, 1945-1959 (Folder 3)
  - Alfange, Dean, 1948-1957 (Folder 4)
  - Alland, Frank, 1961 (Folder 5)
  - Allen, Douglas, 1951 (Folder 6)
  - Allen, Steve, 1961 (Folder 7)
  - Allman, Norwood Francis, 1919-1960 (Folder 8)
  - Alumni Federation of Columbia University, 1950-1956 (Folder 9)
  - Alvord, D. Fletcher, 1961-1962 (Folder 10)
  - Amberg, Richard, 1946-1962 (Folder 11)
  - American Broadcasting Corporation (ABC)
    - 1948-1949 (Folder 12)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - 1952-1961 (Folder 2)
  - American Council for Judaism, 1945 (Folder 3)
  - American Economic Foundation, 1940-1947. Includes correspondence with Fred G. Clark and Richard S. Rimanoczy (Folder 4)
  - American Express Co., 1948-1949 (Folder 5)
  - The American Hebrew, 1939-1947 (Folder 6)
  - The American Jewish Committee, 1939-1956 (Folder 7)
  - The American Legion, 1950-1962 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - The American Magazine, 1934-1938. Includes correspondence with Sumner Blossom (Folder 2)
  - American Management Association, 1961 (Folder 3)
  - The American Mercury, 1934-1945. Includes correspondence with Henry Haslitt, Paul Palmer, and Lawrence E. Spivak (Folder 4)
  - American Relief Administration Association, 1941-1957 (Folder 5)
  - American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals (ASPCA), 1948-1954 (Folder 6)
  - The American Weekly, 1952-1958 (Folder 7)
  - American Writers Association, 1946-1959 (Folder 8)
  - Ancker, Mason, 1951-1953 (Folder 9)
  - Andersen, Martin, 1961 (Folder 10)
  - Anderson, Clinton P., 1959 (Folder 11)
  - Anderson, David L., 1943 (Folder 12)
  - Anderson, Maxcy, 1961 (Folder 13)
  - Anderson, Roy
    - 1920-1921 (Folder 14)
    - 1922-1925 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Anderson, Roy, II, 1946-1956 (Folder 2)
  - Andrews, Henry Maxwell, Mrs. (Rebecca West), 1955 (Folder 3)
  - Andrews, T. Coleman, 1955-1959 (Folder 4)
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, 1951-1962 (Folder 5)
  - Archibald, Fred I., 1961-1962 (Folder 6)
  - Arens, Richard, 1956-1960 (Folder 7)
  - Arnold, Julean, 1919-1920 (Folder 8)
  - Arnold, Paul, 1950-1960 (Folder 9)
  - The Ashland Daily Press. Includes correspondence with John B. Chapple
    - 1946-1949 (Folder 10)
    - 1950-1952 (Folder 11)
  - Astor, Viscount and Lady, 1930-1955 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - The Atlantic Monthly. Includes correspondence with Edward C. Aswell, Ellery Sedgwick, Donald Snyder, and Edward Weeks
    - 1932-1934 (Folder 2)
    - 1935-1936 (Folder 3)
    - 1937-1944 (Folder 4)
  - Atwood, Albert, 1956-1962 (Folder 5)
  - The Authors' League of America, 1941-1948 (Folder 6)
  - Badt, Harry, 1944-1946 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Baily, T. F., 1944-1945 (Folder 2)
  - Baker, Newton D., 1933 (Folder 3)
  - Baker, Raymond C., 1956-1959 (Folder 4)
  - Balaban, Barney, 1956-1959 (Folder 5)
  - Baldwin, Joseph Clark, 1943-1945 (Folder 6)
  - Ballantine, Arthur,1937-1943 (Folder 7)
  - The Baltimore News-Post, 1953-1958 (Folder 8)
  - The Bangor Daily News, 1944-1951 (Folder 9)
  - Barcalo, Edward J., 1936-1956 (Folder 10)
  - Barger, Harry S., 1945-1951 (Folder 11)
  - Barker, Robert, 1946-1952 (Folder 12)
  - Barnard College, 1952-1962 (Folder 13)
  - Barnes, Earl T., 1955 (Folder 14)
  - Barnes, Joseph and Betty, 1932-1934 (Folder 15)
  - Barnes, Eugene E., 1945-1949 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Baroukh, Daniel F., 1955 (Folder 2)
  - The Barre Daily Times, 1951 (Folder 3)
  - Barrett, Alfred, 1950 (Folder 4)
  - Barrett, Edward W., 1957-1961 (Folder 5)
  - Barrett, Richard P., 1946-1947 (Folder 6)
  - Barron, Bryton, 1961 (Folder 7)
  - Barton, Bruce, 1938-1951 (Folder 8)
  - Barton, Winifred, 1928 (Folder 9)
  - Baruch, Bernard, 1935-1962 (Folder 10)
  - Bassett, Arthur, 1920-1960 (Folder 11)
  - Batchelor, Bronson, 1945-1946 (Folder 12)
  - Batchelor, C. D., 1945-1959 (Folder 13)
  - Bayley, Arnold, 1961-1962 (Folder 14)
  - Beach, Roy, 1955 (Folder 15)
  - Beale, Thomas W., 1954 (Folder 16)
  - Beall, Harry S., 1961-1962 (Folder 17)
  - Beall, Jack, 1948-1950 (Folder 18)
  - Bealle, Morris, 1953 (Folder 19)
  - Beard, Charles A., 1919-1948 (Folder 20)
  - Beasley, Norman, 1953 (Folder 21)
  - Becker, Neal Dow, 1948-1955 (Folder 22)
  - Bei, Bao-shan, 1925 (Folder 23)
  - Ben-Horin, Eliahu, 1943-1958 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Bena, Adolfo, 1947-1949 (Folder 2)
  - Bennet, William
    - 1938-1944 (Folder 3)
    - 1945-1958 (Folder 4)
  - Bennett, Lowell, 1961 (Folder 5)
  - Benson, Ezra Taft, 1953-1958 (Folder 6)
  - Benson, George S., 1944-1953 (Folder 7)
  - Bentley, Elizabeth, 1955-1960 (Folder 8)
  - Benz, W. Raymond, Mrs., 1944-1949 (Folder 9)
  - Berkeley, Martin, 1952-1957 (Folder 10)
  - Berkson, Seymour, 1952-1958 (Folder 11)
  - Berlin, Irving, 1944-1945 (Folder 12)
  - Berlin, Richard E. (Box 24)
    - 1944-1949 (Folder 1)
    - 1950-1952 (Folder 2)
    - 1953-1957 (Folder 3)
    - 1958-1962 (Folder 4)
  - Bernays, Edward L., 1937-1946 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Bernstein, Leonard, 1953 (Folder 2)
  - Berrier, Hilaire du, 1959 (Folder 3)
  - Bethlehem Steel Co., 1938-1943. Includes correspondence with Joseph Larkin and John Long (Folder 4)
  - Bielaski, Frank B., 1951-1953 (Folder 5)
  - Bez, Nick, 1949-1951 (Folder 6)
  - Bill of Rights Commemorative Society, 1950-1952 (Folder 7)
  - Billikopf, Jacob, 1948-1951 (Folder 8)
  - Binder, Carroll, 1933 (Folder 9)
  - Binder, Frank K., 1950-1951 (Folder 10)
  - Bingham, Hiram, Mr. and Mrs., 1927-1928 (Folder 11)
  - Bingham, Woodbridge, 1928-1929 (Folder 12)
  - Birchall, Frederick T., 1933-1935 (Folder 13)
  - The Birmingham News, 1962 (Folder 14)
  - Birmingham, Donald, 1962 (Folder 15)
  - Bisson, T. A., 1931-1935 (Folder 16)
  - Black, Ione, 1920 (Folder 17)
  - Black, René, 1951-1960 (Folder 18)
  - Black, Thomas, 1929-1933 (Folder 19)
  - Blake, Harry, 1961-1962 (Folder 20)
  - Blakeslee, George W., 1927-1932 (Folder 21)
  - Blanchard, Edwin H., 1947-1961 (Folder 22)
  - Blankfort, Michael, 1952-1954 (Folder 23)
  - Blitzer, Charles, 1947-1956 (Folder 24)
  - Bloch, Joshua, 1946-1954 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Block, Paul, 1937-1939 (Folder 2)
  - Blumenthal, Charles, 1918-1936 (Folder 3)
  - Blumenthal, Morton, 1943-1950 (Folder 4)
  - Bobich, Gica, 1959 (Folder 5)
  - Bodley, Ronald, 1955 (Folder 6)
  - Bodman, E. J., 1947-1948 (Folder 7)
  - Boehnken, Olga H., 1955-1956 (Folder 8)
  - Bohn, William E., 1941 (Folder 9)
  - Bohnsack, Christie, 1953 (Folder 10)
  - Bolger, Robert V., 1950-1951 (Folder 11)
  - Bolton, Frances P., 1942-1949 (Folder 12)
  - Bolton, George, Sir, 1955 (Folder 13)
  - Bond, Ward, Mr. and Mrs., 1951
    - 1951 (Folder 14)
    - 1952 (Folder 15)
    - 1953-1956 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - 1957-1960 (Folder 2)
  - Bondy, Terence, 1951 (Folder 3)
  - Booker, Edna May, 1939 (Folder 4)
  - Boomer, Lucius, 1939-1947 (Folder 5)
  - Boorstin, Samuel, 1952 (Folder 6)
  - Borah, William E., 1933 (Folder 7)
  - Boston Record-American, 1946-1960. Includes correspondence with Ernest Hoftyzer and H. G. Kern (Folder 8)
  - Boxer, Jeda, 1949 (Folder 9)
  - Bowles, Chester, 1959-1962 (Folder 10)
  - Brande, Samuel, 1960-1961 (Folder 11)
  - Brandeis, Erich, 1948-1949 (Folder 12)
  - Brandeis University, 1948 (Folder 13)
  - Branscombe, Harvie, 1948-1955 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Bratter, Herbert
    - 1922-1926 (Folder 2)
    - 1927-1961 (Folder 3)
  - Braunstein, Leon, 1948 (Folder 4)
  - The Brearley School, 1946-1958 (Folder 5)
  - Brede, William, 1950-1962 (Folder 6)
  - Breech, Ernest, 1955 (Folder 7)
  - Breen, Joseph, 1945-1951 (Folder 8)
  - Breitel, Charles D., 1948-1950 (Folder 9)
  - Brennan, Thomas A., 1945-1961 (Folder 10)
  - Brewer, Roy (Box 29)
    - 1952-1953 (Folder 1)
    - 1954-1961 (Folder 2)
  - Brewster, Owen, 1947-1956 (Folder 3)
  - Brick, Terry, 1941-1947 (Folder 4)
  - Bricker, John W., 1942-1958 (Folder 5)
  - The Bridgeport Post, 1947-1952 (Folder 6)
  - Bridges, Styles, Mr. and Mrs., 1947-1961 (Folder 7)
  - Breirton, Dorothy, 1960 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Brisbane, Arthur, 1934 (Folder 2)
  - Brogan, John A., Jr., 1948-1962 (Folder 3)
  - Brogan, John A., III, 1948 (Folder 4)
  - Brooks, Myrtiss, 1953 (Folder 5)
  - Brooks, Rachel, 1922-1930 (Folder 6)
  - Brooks, Walter H., 1943-1944 (Folder 7)
  - Brophy, Edward F., 1946 (Folder 8)
  - Brosseau, Grace, 1950-1958 (Folder 9)
  - Brothers, Gladys S., 1945-1947 (Folder 10)
  - Broun, Heywood, 1934 (Folder 11)
  - Brown, Carey H., 1952 (Folder 12)
  - Brown, Clarence J., 1947-1956 (Folder 13)
  - Brown, Constantine, Mrs., 1951-1956 (Folder 14)
  - Brown, James Wright, 1950-1959 (Folder 15)
  - Brown, Peter Campbell, 1956-1962 (Folder 16)
  - Brown, Roscoe, 1938 (Folder 17)
  - Brown, Walter T., 1955-1960 (Folder 18)
  - Brown, William K., 1951 (Folder 19)
  - Browne, James Donald, 1960 (Folder 20)
  - Brownell, Herbert, 1945-1953 (Folder 21)
  - Brundage, Avery, 1959 (Folder 22)
  - The Brush-Moore Newspapers, Inc., 1944-1955 (Folder 23)
  - Bryant, Dorothy, 1950-1953 (Folder 24)
  - Bryant, Stewart, 1920 (Folder 25)
  - Buchanan, Eleanor, 1951 (Folder 26)
  - Buckley, Daniel G. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Buckley, William F., Jr., 1947-1962 (Folder 2)
  - Buckley, William F., Sr., 1948-1955 (Folder 3)
  - Buckman, Frank, 1951 (Folder 4)
  - Budd, Edward G., 1943-1944 (Folder 5)
  - Budenz, Louis, 1952 (Folder 6)
  - Buell, Raymond Leslie, 1932-1933 (Folder 7)
  - The Bulletin Co., 1949-1958 (Folder 8)
  - Burch, Guy Irving, 1948 (Folder 9)
  - Burger, George J., 1948 (Folder 10)
  - Burke, John, 1938-1962 (Folder 11)
  - Burns, Jane, 1957-1958 (Folder 12)
  - Burns, John, 1947-1955 (Folder 13)
  - Burrell, Alice, 1940-1953 (Folder 14)
  - Burt, Hardy, 1954-1960 (Folder 15)
  - Burton, Harold, 1943. Includes correspondence with George A. Torsney (Folder 16)
  - Busch, Noel, Mrs., 1949 (Folder 17)
  - Butler, Hugh, 1947-1948 (Folder 18)
  - Butler, Karl (Box 32)
    - 1950-1954 (Folder 1)
    - 1955-1958 (Folder 2)
    - 1959-1961 (Folder 3)
  - Butler, Nicolas Murray, 1943 (Folder 4)
  - Bynner, Witter, 1920-1955 (Folder 5)
  - Byrd, Harry F., 1950-1961 (Folder 6)
  - Byrd, Robert C., 1957 (Folder 7)
  - Byrnes, James F., 1948 (Folder 8)
  - Byroade, Henry A., 1960-1961 (Folder 9)
  - Cahn, Julius N., 1952-1959 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Calder, Bland, 1918-1933 (Folder 2)
  - Caldwell, Taylor, 1949-1962 (Folder 3)
  - Calomiris, Angela, 1951-1956 (Folder 4)
  - Cameron, George T., 1935-1942 (Folder 5)
  - Cameron, Robertson, 1950 (Folder 6)
  - Campbell, F. W., 1959-1961 (Folder 7)
  - Campbell, Reginald, 1951 (Folder 8)
  - Cantor, Eddie, 1936-1961 (Folder 9)
  - Caplan, Elliott, 1951 (Folder 10)
  - Capps, James G., 1948-1950 (Folder 11)
  - Carey, David, 1961 (Folder 12)
  - Carey, H. Lansing, 1950-1960 (Folder 13)
  - Carey, Northrop, 1944 (Folder 14)
  - Carey, Ocean D., 1948-1949 (Folder 15)
  - Carpenter, Harry, Mrs., 1940-1941 (Folder 16)
  - Carpenter, Harry, Jr., Mr. and Mrs., 1941 (Folder 17)
  - Carr, Eugene, 1949-1956 (Folder 18)
  - Carr, Francis P., 1953-1954 (Folder 19)
  - Carrier Corporation, 1950 (Folder 20)
  - Carroll, Louis D., 1950-1952 (Folder 21)
  - Carter, Boake, 1937-1942 (Folder 22)
  - Carter, Edward C., 1929-1947 (Folder 23)
  - Carter, Fred M., 1949-1950 (Folder 24)
  - Case, Clifford P., 1959-1962 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Cassini, Igor, 1948-1962 (Folder 2)
  - Castillo, Juan J. del, 1951 (Folder 3)
  - Castle, Eugene, 1956-1959 (Folder 4)
  - Castle, William R., 1940-1943 (Folder 5)
  - The Catholic Actors Guild of America, 1944-1961 (Folder 6)
  - Catholic War Veterans Inc., 1946-1960 (Folder 7)
  - The Catholic World, 1946-1952 (Folder 8)
  - Central Synagogue (New York), 1933-1962 (Folder 9)
  - Cerf, Bennett, 1944-1962 (Folder 10)
  - Chadbourne, William, 1940-1953 (Folder 11)
  - Chamberlain, John, 1951 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Chambers, Whittaker, 1952-1953 (Folder 2)
  - Chang, Kia-ngau, 1929-1947 (Folder 3)
  - Chang, Loy, 1930-1931 (Folder 4)
  - Chang, P. H., 1947 (Folder 5)
  - Chapple, John, 1951 (Folder 6)
  - The Charlotte Observer, 1951-1953. Includes correspondence with Ralph Nicholson (Folder 7)
  - Chen, Chih-Mai, 1949-1951 (Folder 8)
  - Chen, Eugene, 1923-1933 (Folder 9)
  - Chen, K. P., 1928-1931 (Folder 10)
  - Chen, L. T., 1931 (Folder 11)
  - Chen, Y. K., 1947 (Folder 12)
  - Chenery, William, 1948-1949 (Folder 13)
  - Chennault, Claire Lee, 1949 (Folder 14)
  - Chester, Colby, 1943 (Folder 15)
  - Chiang, May-Ling Soong, 1925-1962 (Folder 16)
  - Childs Company, 1934 (Folder 17)
  - China Institute in America, 1951 (Folder 18)
  - Chinese Art Society of America, 1944-1945 (Folder 19)
  - Chinese News Service, 1948-1950 (Folder 20)
  - Christenberry, Robert K., 1949-1961 (Folder 21)
  - Ciletti, Lucian J., 1951-1953 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Cima, Anthony P., 1946-1948 (Folder 2)
  - Circumnavigators Club, 1939-1956 (Folder 3)
  - Citizens, Inc., 1944-1945 (Folder 4)
  - Citizens Committee for the Hoover Report, 1949-1957 (Folder 5)
  - Clairborne, Elizabeth, 1943-1944 (Folder 6)
  - Clapp, Paul S., 1943-1945 (Folder 7)
  - Clarey, Northrup, 1939-1944 (Folder 8)
  - Clark, Fred G., 1962 (Folder 9)
  - Clark, Mark W., 1961-1962 (Folder 10)
  - Clarke, Harley L., 1945-1953 (Folder 11)
  - Clay, Lucius D., 1950 (Folder 12)
  - Clemens, Cyril, 1951-1962 (Folder 13)
  - Clement, Charles Francis, 1944-1945 (Folder 14)
  - Clement, Martin W., 1944-1956 (Folder 15)
  - Clements, John, 1956-1960 (Folder 16)
  - Cleveland Plain Dealer, 1950-1952 (Folder 17)
  - Close, Upton, 1948-1953 (Folder 18)
  - Coblentz, Edmond D., 1946-1950 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Cohen, Harry, 1957 (Folder 2)
  - Cohen, J. X., 1934 (Folder 3)
  - Cohen, Mickey, 1957 (Folder 4)
  - Cohn, Albert, 1954-1957 (Folder 5)
  - Cohn, James, 1957 (Folder 6)
  - Cohn, Roy, 1953-1954 (Folder 7)
  - Col Dragonette, Kyra du, 1957 (Folder 8)
  - Coll, Raymond, 1956-1957 (Folder 9)
  - Collier, C. H., 1951 (Folder 10)
  - Collingwood, Charles, 1961 (Folder 11)
  - Collins, E. D., 1949-1950 (Folder 12)
  - Collins, Stephen, 1959-1960 (Folder 13)
  - Collins, Wilkie Nelson, 1932-1936 (Folder 14)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System (CBS), 1938-1957 (Folder 15)
  - Columbia Journalism Alumni, 1959-1962 (Folder 16)
  - Columbia Lecture Bureau, 1952 (Folder 17)
  - Columbia News Service, 1941-1944 (Folder 18)
  - Columbia University, 1938-1962. Includes correspondence with Herbert Brucker, Frank Fackenthal, and Grayson Kirk (Folder 19)
  - The Columbus Dispatch, 1942-1959 (Folder 20)
  - The Commentator, 1936-1939. Includes correspondence with Hawthorne Daniel (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Conniff, Frank, 1957-1961 (Folder 2)
  - Considine, Bob, 1949-1958 (Folder 3)
  - Coogan, Aloysius F., 1948-1954 (Folder 4)
  - Cooke, Charles M., 1959 (Folder 5)
  - Corbin, John C., 1945-1946 (Folder 6)
  - Corson, Forrest E., 1952-1959 (Folder 7)
  - Cosmopolitan, 1938-1958 (Folder 8)
  - Coudert, Frederic R.
    - 1937-1952 (Folder 9)
    - 1953-1960 (Folder 10)
  - Cousins, Garnett, 1930-1950 (Folder 11)
  - Cousins, Norman, 1951-1962 (Folder 12)
  - Cowles, Elizabeth S., 1950-1961 (Folder 13)
  - Cox, Eugene, 1952 (Folder 14)
  - Cox, Robert H., Mr. and Mrs., 1940 (Folder 15)
  - Cragin, John, 1950-1959 (Folder 16)
  - Craig, James E., 1943-1947 (Folder 17)
  - Crain, Lucille Cardin, 1949-1951 (Folder 18)
  - Cravath, Paul D. (Box 39)
    - 1930-1933 (Folder 1)
    - 1934-1940 (Folder 2)
  - Crawford, Joan, 1960 (Folder 3)
  - Creel, George, 1947-1953 (Folder 4)
  - Criscuolo, Luigi, 1941-1955 (Folder 5)
  - Cronkite, Walter, 1960 (Folder 6)
  - Cross, Harold, 1944 (Folder 7)
  - Crow, Allen, 1949 (Folder 8)
  - Crow, Carl, 1938-1944 (Folder 9)
  - Crowther, Samuel, 1944-1947 (Folder 10)
  - Crozier, William, Mr. and Mrs., 1921-1933 (Folder 11)
  - Crum, Bartley, 1952-1953 (Folder 12)
  - Cullman, Howard S., 1947-1954 (Folder 13)
  - Cumming, Hugh, Jr., 1933-1934 (Folder 14)
  - Cumming, Peter M., 1961-1962 (Folder 15)
  - Cunningham, Edwin S. (Box 40)
    - 1919-1928 (Folder 1)
    - 1929-1953 (Folder 2)
  - Cured Cancer Club, 1960-1961 (Folder 3)
  - Curran, Thomas, 1941-1958 (Folder 4)
  - Custer, Calvin (Carlos Garcia), 1921-1949 (Folder 5)
  - Cvetic, Matt, 1952-1959 (Folder 6)
  - The Dallas Morning News, 1947-1955 (Folder 7)
  - Daly, John T., 1958-1962 (Folder 8)
  - Danskin, Hannah, 1939-1949 (Folder 9)
  - Darr, John W., 1953 (Folder 10)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution, 1937-1960 (Folder 11)
  - Davie, Emily, 1941-1956 (Folder 12)
  - Davie, Preston, Mr. and Mrs., 1943-1961 (Folder 13)
  - Davies, John R., 1941-1948 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Davis, Warren Jefferson, 1961 (Folder 2)
  - Day, Samuel, 1955-1961 (Folder 3)
  - Deasy, John F., Mr. and Mrs., 1943-1948 (Folder 4)
  - Debuchi, K., 1923-1931 (Folder 5)
  - De Courcy, Kenneth Hugh, 1949-1951 (Folder 6)
  - Deegan, William, 1932-1947 (Folder 7)
  - DeLany, Walter S., 1952-1953 (Folder 8)
  - DeLoach, C. D., 1959-1962 (Folder 9)
  - Demarest, L. M., 1949-1950 (Folder 10)
  - Dennis, Lawrence, 1943-1948 (Folder 11)
  - Denny, George V., 1933-1949 (Folder 12)
  - DeSapio, Carmine, 1956-1961 (Folder 13)
  - Desmond, Thomas C., 1938-1955 (Folder 14)
  - Desvernine, Gilbert, 1942-1960 (Folder 15)
  - Desvernine, Raoul Eugene
    - 1942-1944 (Folder 16)
    - 1945-1948 (Folder 17)
  - De Toledano, Ralph, 1950-1959 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Detroit Times, 1947-1954 (Folder 2)